Welcome to this expense agent [music]
series where we are going to look behind
the scenes what happens
in BC when somebody makes expenses in
the web app.
Our product designer Lena,
uh she's going to visit a customer
in relation to a project we are having.
And um of course she's going to make
some expenses in that regard.
And
we're going to see a bit about how data
is flowing through our system
automatically.
So one thing that Lena cannot
do herself is uh specify dimensions, but
we'll look at how we use the default
dimensions
to track through the system.
And we we start with um Lena herself.
Uh she is employed in the product
department because she is a product
designer.
She is also a sales person.
Um
so she has these two dimensions connect
to her.
And then at some point she has rented a
car and she submits the expense for it.
Um
and
where you could see that is if you look
at then the dimensions that
automatically are attached to that
expense, uh you get it from
>> [snorts]
>> what Lena had, department prod and sales
person Lena.
And then the accountant can choose to
add or move um dimensions. So in this
case the accountant has added a business
group.
And at some point Lena is done, so she
turns the expense into an expense report
and obviously normally she would have
more, some hotel or whatever.
For this case we'll just look at this
one liner. So this is a project, so
because it was a project meeting, so she
can click on um um
show billable information about this
expense she had.
And there she can assign
the uh expense to a customer. She can
even specify
which account in our system it should go
to, the expense.
And she can specify a project
uh and project task number that this is
linked to.
And all of these
sources, if you will, uh combine to a
new set of dimensions. So, we retrieve
dimensions from all of these
uh
inputs.
So, once this um
expense report looks correct,
we can start posting um
the uh report, and we can then
look at what entries are created from
this report.
The expense is approved and posted.
We end up with a posted expense report,
obviously.
And if you look at which entries have
been created,
you can see that uh we are obviously
have the
expense report itself, but there's also
project ledger entry, as you can see in
the bottom.
And there's also
a ledger entry for the employee,
because now we owe Lena this money.
So, let's take a look at how do we pay
out the money to the employee, the money
that we owe her?
Well, first of we can go in uh
on her employee card
and actually see, yes, this is the
expense she had, $401.
And then there's a
function called pay employee
that you can press, which opens up um
all the entries we owe her, in this case
only one.
And from there we can create a payment
which just opens the normal
payment journal.
And as you can see that we now have an
account type that's called employee.
Previously,
it would have been only a vendor, but
now we can also pay out to employees.
Finally,
let's also see how
Lina's expense affects the project.
If we look at the project she she
specified,
you can see that under billable cost
under that spec thing she
attended a meeting for,
the money is also registered there.
And if you look at it,
you can see that it's
posted as other travel expenses.
So, in this video we saw how data flows
from Lina's submission of an expense and
all the way through uh
employee ledger entries and out to the
resulting project.
Thanks for watching.